<resources>
    <string name="app_name">My Dzikir App</string>

    <string name="txt_judul_fitur">Kumpulan Doa &amp; Dzikir Sehari-Hari</string>
    <string name="txt_sunnah_qauliyah">Sunnah-Sunnah Qauliyah \nDzikir &amp; Doa Shalat</string>
    <string name="txt_dzikir_setiap_saat">Dzikir Setiap Saat</string>
    <string name="txt_dzikir_doa_harian">Dzikir &amp; Doa Harian</string>
    <string name="txt_dzikir_pagi_petang"><![CDATA[Dzikir Pagi & Petang]]></string>

    <string name="txt_artikel_islami">Artikel Islami</string>

    <string name="txt_dzikir_pagi">Dzikir Pagi</string>
    <string name="txt_dzikir_petang">Dzikir Petang</string>

    <string name="content_txt_icon_dzikir_pagi_petang">Icon Dzikir Pagi Petang</string>
    <string name="content_txt_icon_dzikir_doa_harian">Icon Dzikir Doa Harian</string>
    <string name="content_txt_icon_dzikir_setiap_saat">Icon Dzikir Setiap Saat</string>
    <string name="content_txt_icon_qauliyah_shalat">Icon Qauliyah Shalat</string>
    <string name="content_txt_icon_btn_dzikir_pagi">Icon btn dzikir Pagi</string>
    <string name="content_txt_icon_btn_dzikir_petang">Icon btn Dzikir Petang</string>
    <string name="content_txt_icon_image_for_background_dzikir">Icon image for Background Dzikir</string>
    <string name="content_txt_image_artikel">Image Poster Detail Artikel</string>


    <string-array name="arr_img_artikel">
        <item>@drawable/artikel_1</item>
        <item>@drawable/artikel_2</item>
        <item>@drawable/artikel_3</item>
        <item>@drawable/artikel_4</item>
        <item>@drawable/artikel_5</item>
        <item>@drawable/artikel_6</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="arr_title_artikel">
        <item>Sedekah Adalah Bukti Keimanan</item>
        <item>Hukum Fotografi Dalam Islam</item>
        <item>Why Does Allah Test Our Faith?</item>
        <item>Lesson Learned By A Muslim Traveler</item>
        <item>Merits of The Soul: Patience(Sabr)</item>
        <item>The Importance of Seeking Knowledge</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="arr_desc_artikel">
        <item>Salah satu cara kita mengetahui kadar keimanan kita adalah dengan melihat apakah kita suka bersedekah atau tidak.
            /n/nBersedekah tidak harus banyak dan tidak harus dengan uang, sehingga tidak kaya atau tidak punya uang bukanlah menjadi alasan kita untuk tidak bersedekah.
            Bersedekah dengan uang Rp 10.000, Rp 20.000, atau Rp 50.000 itu sudah cukup. Atau bersedekah dengan beras yang kita miliki sebanyak satu kilo atau dua kilo, ini pun sudah cukup.
            /n/nSedekah adalah bukti keimanan.
            /n/nBukti keimanan kita terhadap hari akhir, bahwasanya kelak di hari kiamat kita akan mendapat balasan pahala dari Allah, meskipun di dunia kita tidak mendapatkan apa-apa. Kita lelah bekerja mencari uang dan harta, lalu uang tersebut kita berikan tanpa kompensasi dan kita hanya berharap balasan di hari kiamat kelak.</item>
        <item>Hukum melukis makhluk bernyawa
            \n\nDari Abu Hurairah radhiyallahu anhu, ia berkata:
            \nSaya mendengar Nabi ﷺ bersabda,/nقَالَ اللَّهُ عَزَّ وَجَلَّ وَمَنْ أَظْلَمُ مِمَّنْ ذَهَبَ يَخْلُقُ كَخَلْقِي فَلْيَخْلُقُوا بَعُوضَةً أَوْ لِيَخْلُقُوا ذَرَّةً

            \n\n“Allah ‘Azza wa Jalla berfirman, “Siapakah yang lebih zholim daripada orang yang berkehendak mencipta seperti ciptaan-Ku. Coba mereka menciptakan lalat atau semut kecil (jika mereka memang mampu)!”\
            \n(HR. Bukhari no. 5953 dan Muslim no. 2111, juga Ahmad 2: 259, dan ini adalah lafazhnya)

            \n\nJuga dari Abu Hurairah dalam riwayat lain disebutkan,\nقَالَ اللَّهُ عَزَّ وَجَلَّ وَمَنْ أَظْلَمُ مِمَّنْ ذَهَبَ يَخْلُقُ كَخَلْقِى ، فَلْيَخْلُقُوا ذَرَّةً ، أَوْ لِيَخْلُقُوا حَبَّةً أَوْ شَعِيرَةً
            \n\“Allah ‘Azza wa Jalla berfirman, “Siapakah yang lebih zholim daripada orang yang mencipta seperti ciptaan-Ku. Coba mereka menciptakan semut kecil, biji atau gandum (jika mereka memang mampu)! ”\
            \n(HR. Bukhari no. 7559)

            \nDari Abdullah bin Mas’ud radhiyallahu ‘anhu dari Nabi shallallahu ‘alaihi wa sallam bahwa beliau bersabda,\n
            إِنَّ أَشَدَّ النَّاسِ عَذَابًا عِنْدَ اللَّهِ يَوْمَ الْقِيَامَةِ الْمُصَوِّرُون
            \n\“Sesungguhnya manusia yang paling keras siksaannya di sisi Allah pada hari kiamat adalah tukang penggambar.”\
            \n(HR. Bukhari no. 5950 dan Muslim no. 2109)

            \n\nDari ‘Abdullah bin ‘Umar radhiyallahu ‘anhuma, dia berkata, Rasulullah ﷺ bersabda:\n
            إِنَّ الَّذِينَ يَصْنَعُونَ هَذِهِ الصُّوَرَ يُعَذَّبُونَ يَوْمَ الْقِيَامَةِ يُقَالُ لَهُمْ أَحْيُوا مَا خَلَقْتُمْ

            \n\“Sesungguhnya mereka yang membuat gambar-gambar akan disiksa pada hari kiamat. Akan dikatakan kepada mereka, “Hidupkanlah apa yang kalian ciptakan.”\
            \n(HR. Bukhari no. 5961 dan Muslim no. 5535)
            \n\nDari Ibnu ‘Abbas radhiyallahu ‘anhuma, ia berkata bahwa Rasulullah ﷺ bersabda,\n
            مَنْ صَوَّرَ صُورَةً عُذِّبَ حَتَّى يَنْفُخَ فِيهَا الرُّوحَ وَلَيْسَ بِنَافِخٍ فِيهَا
            \n\“Barangsiapa yang membuat gambar, ia akan disiksa hingga ia bisa meniupkan ruh pada gambar yang ia buat. Namun kenyataannya ia tidak bisa meniupnya.”\
            \n(HR. An Nasai no. 5359 dan Ahmad 1: 216. Syaikh Al Albani mengatakan bahwa hadits ini shahih)
            \n\nIbnu Taimiyah rahimahullah berkata, “Dalam hadits ini dibedakan antara gambar hewan (yang memiliki ruh, pen) dan bukan hewan. Hal ini mengandung pelajaran bahwa boleh saja menggambar pohon dan benda logam di baju atau kain, dan menggambar yang lain (yang tidak memiliki ruh, pen).” (Majmu’ah Al-Fatawa, 29:370)

            \n\n\nBeda Melukis dan Mengambil Foto
            \n\nDari Sa’id bin Abil Hasan, ia berkata, “Aku dahulu pernah berada di sisi Ibnu ‘Abbas –radhiyallahu ‘anhuma-. Ketika itu ada seseorang yang mendatangi beliau lantas ia berkata, “Wahai Abu ‘Abbas, aku adalah manusia. Penghasilanku berasal dari hasil karya tanganku. Aku biasa membuat gambar seperti ini.” Ibnu ‘Abbas kemudian berkata, “Tidaklah yang kusampaikan berikut ini selain dari yang pernah kudengar dari Rasulullah ﷺ. Aku pernah mendengar beliau bersabda, “Barangsiapa yang membuat gambar, Allah akan mengazabnya hingga ia bisa meniupkan ruh pada gambar yang ia buat. Padahal ia tidak bisa meniupkan ruh tersebut selamanya.” Wajah si pelukis tadi ternyata berubah menjadi kuning. Kata Ibnu ‘Abbas, “Jika engkau masih tetap ingin melukis, maka gambarlah pohon atau segala sesuatu yang tidak memiliki ruh.”
            \n(HR. Bukhari no. 2225)
            \n\nHadits di atas membicarakan pelukis yang mereka-reka gambar makhluk bernyawa sehingga menghasilkan gambar baru yang menyerupai ciptaan Allah. Adapun foto dari kamera berbeda. Foto hasil kamera adalah gambar ciptaan Allah itu sendiri. Sehingga hal ini tidak termasuk dalam gambar yang nanti diperintahkan untuk ditiupkan ruhnya. Foto yang dihasilkan dari kamera ibarat hasil cermin. Para ulama bersepakat akan bolehnya gambar yang ada di cermin.

            \n\n\nHukum Fotografi
            \n\nTerkait foto makhluk bernyawa, bagaimana hukum memotret makhluk hidup?
            \n\nPendapat pertama, diharamkan memotret dan hasil fotonya, kecuali untuk suatu yang penting seperti paspor, KTP, ijazah, dan dokumen penting lainnya. Alasannya, karena memotret sama dengan menggambar.
            \n\nPendapat kedua, hukumnya dibolehkan selagi memenuhi kaidah:\n
            \n* Bukan gambar wanita
            \n* Bukan gambar laki-laki yang membuka aurat
            \n* Tidak dipajang di dinding, di pinggir jalan, dan tempat keramaian
            \n\nDalilnya, melukis dan memotret berbeda. Memotret itu sama seperti asli (layaknya cermin). Melukis itu mesti mereka-mereka.
            \n\nHukum asalnya, memotret itu boleh. Menjual hasil pemotretan juga boleh, selama memperhatikan kaidah umum syariat Islam dalam pemotretan.
            \n\nSemoga bermanfaat.</item>
        <item>Today we’re going to discuss an important part of Islam, which is the topic of trials and tests. There’s a lot of things that we can talk about when it comes to this subject, but let’s focus on two basic questions: why does Allah test us  what should our attitude be when facing a test from Allah?
            \n\nWhy does Allah test us?
            \n\n“It is He who created death and life to test which of you are best in deeds, for He is the Almighty, the Forgiving.” (Qur’an 67:2)
            \n\nMany religions preach that trials and tests are always sent as punishment from God. They claim that if you are afflicted with a hardship, such as sickness or loss of wealth, it means you have somehow displeased God.
            \n\nHowever, this is NOT true in Islam. In Islam, there is no correlation between our present situation and Allah’s attitude toward us.
            \n\nFor example, if I lose my job, it doesn’t mean that Allah is angry at me. On the other hand, if I get a pay raise at my job, it doesn’t mean that Allah is happy with me. Instead, Allah presents us with these different situations to see how we react to them.
            \n\nIn the above Quranic verse, Allah tells us that tests and trials are a part of life. Everyone will be tested to a certain extent at times so that Allah can see which person has true faith in him. In other words, He will see who is doing good deeds for the right reason and who only does good deeds when it is convenient.
            \n\nProphet Muhammad ﷺ said:
            \n\n“Nothing befalls a believer, a (prick of a) thorn or more than that, but Allah will raise him one degree in status thereby, or erase a bad deed.” (Bukhari)
            \n\nThis hadith shows us the two general reasons a test may occur in somebody’s life. The first reason is that Allah will test you with something so that you have the opportunity to successfully go through the test with the right attitude, and Allah will therefore raise your station in Paradise.
            \n\nThe second reason for facing a trial is that I may have done something wrong and I may not have asked Allah for forgiveness. Instead of punishing me in the Hereafter, Allah will put me through something in this life.
            \n\nWhatever He puts me through in this life will be nothing like what I would have faced in the Hereafter, so this trial is actually a form of Allah’s mercy.
            \n\nWhat should a Muslim’s attitude be when faced with a test or trial?
            \n\nNow that we know the reasons for tests and trials, let’s examine how we as Muslims should respond when faced with a test. The first thing is to keep it all in perspective.

            \n\n1. KEEP IT IN PERSPECTIVE
            \n\nAllah does not burden a soul beyond that it can bear.” (Qur’an 2:286)
            \n\nA person will never be faced with a bigger hardship than they can handle. A lot of times, when we’re going through a trial, we become so focused on the trial that we lose sight of everything else. For example, if a person loses a job, they will often focus on what they don’t have and will forget what they do have, such as their health, family, or (if nothing else) their faith.
            \n\nFocusing on what we have versus what problems we’re faced with allows us to keep a good attitude about situations, and knowing that Allah will never give us more than we can handle helps us keep everything in perspective. Keeping the perspective that Allah never gives a person a trial that’s bigger than what they can handle reminds us that no matter what it may be, we should never lose hope or lose patience because we already know we will get through it.

            \n\n2. ALLAH ALWAYS DOES WHAT’S BEST FOR US
            \n\n“And it may be that you dislike a thing which is good for you and that you like a thing which is bad for you. Allah knows but you do not know.” (Qur’an, 2:216)
            \n\nAllah is reminding us of something very important here. He is saying that when we are faced with something, we see the here and now. We don’t truly understand the big picture. Therefore, we see things as good or bad because we can only see what’s physically happening in the present.
            \n\nAn easy example to understand is the example of getting a flat tire on the road. Nobody wants to deal with a flat tire because it’s an inconvenience. However, imagine that down the road there was a drunk driver who was out of control. Perhaps by giving us a flat tire, Allah saved us from being harmed by the drunk driver.
            \n\nOne thing we must realize is that Allah will never put us through a trial for no reason. There are several authentic hadiths where Prophet Muhammad ﷺ mentioned that Allah loves us more than our own mothers. A mother would never willingly put their child through a hardship for no reason at all. Therefore, it is safe to say that neither would Allah. Every trial or test has a purpose behind it, even if we cannot comprehend it at the time.
            \n\nWith that in mind, here’s an analogy to show how we sometimes can’t see why we’re put through a trial until after we’ve gone through it. When I was younger, my parents were very strict on how much dessert or soda I could have. As a child, I saw these restrictions as unfair. However, now as an adult, I’ve come to realize that they were doing it for my own good. They didn’t want me to intake that much sugar so that I would grow up healthy. Back then, I could only see the here and now and thought they were being cruel to me. However, in reality, my parents were thinking about my future and doing what they knew was best for me even if I didn’t understand it.
            \n\nAllah does the same thing for us. Sometimes we may really want something and not get it, or we might face some hardship. It’s easy to get focused on the here and now and be tempted to question Allah. However, if we remember how much Allah cares about us, we realize that He is actually doing what is best for us in the long run.

            \n\n3. REMEMBER THE IMPORTANCE OF THANKFULNESS AND PATIENCE
            \n\nProphet Muhammad ﷺ said:
            \n\n“Wondrous is the affair of the believer for there is good for him in every matter and this is not the case with anyone except the believer. If he is happy, then he thanks Allah and thus there is good for him. If he is harmed, then he shows patience and thus there is good for him.” (Muslim)
            \n\nThis is one hadith that we should always keep at the forefront of our minds. There are very few periods in our lives where things are simply neutral. Most of the time, things seem to be progressing or it seems as if the entire world has turned against us.
            \n\nOne of the aspects I love above the above hadith is that it shows us how powerful our attitude is because our attitude shows Allah our faith in Him. Our attitude can make a positive situation better and turn a negative situation into a positive situation. In other words, if things are going well and we remain thankful and humble, Allah will turn a good situation into a great situation. As Allah promises in verse 7 of Surah Ibrahim, when we are thankful, He will give us more, Insha Allah.
            \n\nOn the other hand, if things are not going well but we remain patient and steadfast (i.e. have sabr), then Allah will bring about some good from the situation, and the situation will eventually be alleviated.
            \n\nThis hadith should give us hope that no matter what we’re going through, Allah has not abandoned us. We just need to maintain the right attitude toward the situation and good faith toward Him.

            \n\n4. THE REWARDS OF A TEST ARE ALWAYS GREATER THAN THE TEST ITSELF
            \n\n“Surely there is ease after hardship. Aye, surely there is ease after hardship.” (Qur’an 94:5-6)
            \n\nOne thing scholars have mentioned about this verse is that by the use of a definite article in the Arabic text, the two verses refer to the same difficulty, but they refer to different eases or rewards.
            \n\nIn other words, Allah is telling us that every trial we go through, if faced with the right attitude, will result in multiple rewards that are greater than the trial itself!

            \n\n With this in mind, knowing that Allah has promised us a victory for facing hardships with the right attitude, it is much easier to stay steadfast in times of trials.
            \n\nAn excellent example of what this verse means is shown in the life of Prophet Muhammad ﷺ. After preaching Islam in Mecca for close to thirteen years, there were only a handful of Muslims in the city when the migration to Medina occurred.
            \n\nHowever, just ten years later, the entire Arabian Peninsula had converted to Islam, and tens of thousands of Muslims accompanied Prophet Muhammad ﷺ during his final pilgrimage to Mecca.

            \n\nInsha’Allah may Allah keep us safe from hardships. However, if we face any, may Allah then allow us to face them with patience and with the right attitude.
        </item>
        <item>“O mankind! We have created you from a male and a female, and made you into nations and tribes so that you may know one another…” (Quran 49:13)
            \n\n\nOriginally from Algeria, I studied in very different cities including New York City (USA), Quebec City (Canada) and Osaka (Japan). Due to my thirst for knowledge, I embarked on graduate studies to explore the unknown world and human nature.
            \n\nThese living and educational experiences gave me the opportunity to learn about very different aspects of natural science by conducting experiments in laboratories, and also to further discover diverse facets of human nature by interacting with different cultures, religions and social backgrounds. With commitment to my Muslim heritage, my biggest challenge was to seek an understanding of differences without necessarily adopting them.
            \n\nAs if I were searching for something deep inside me, naively I removed my cultural slippers to feel the warmth and the coldness of human nature. Therefore, my curiosity pushed me to cross borders in order to explore cultural and religious practices in depth.
            \n\nInitially, I noticed many similarities between human beings, since we often experience emotions for the same reasons. One of my best memories is when some of my friends of different cultures found love and embarked on intercultural marriages.
            \n\nMoreover, while practices and conventions may differ, the underlying motivations and needs that unite human beings are the same. For example, some cultures use cutlery to eat, whereas others use their hands or chopsticks, but everyone is eating for sustenance and survival.
            \n\nSimilarly, the need to communicate and express human feelings encompasses the use of many languages and dialects. The practices of faith also vary widely, which I noticed in detail from visiting churches in New York City and Quebec, and shrines in Japan, and observing religious practices in those special places.
            \n\n\nAt the end of my travels, with my mind full of so many exciting experiences, I went back to Algeria to rest, reflect and consider my future. During the first months in my hometown, I realized that the immersion in different cultures had caused changes within me and my thinking. Since I had the opportunity to discover myself through others, I have come to see humanity as a tree with a single root, with each branch offering a different kind of fruit. As a consequence, I feel more moved by the invisible world than the cultural and physical aspects of our existence.
            \n\nMoreover, since I have been for many years conducting research in different types of scientific fields and utilized diverse theories to interpret data from my experiments, I realized that, if the mathematical models used in different fields of science look different in the application, they have a similar profound concept. I came to the conclusion that these scientific principles could belong to one divine science imposed by Allah (Subhanahu Wata\'ala) on the whole universe.
            \n\n\nIn order to explore the impact of my travel experiences on my faith, I decided to deepen my knowledge in Islam by listening on a daily basis to resources, such as “Tafseer Al Quran” (explanation of Quran) and “Asma Allah Al Husna” (The Beautiful Names of Allah Subhanahu Wata\'ala) by Dr. Mohammed Rateb al-Nabulsi. The messages contained within resonated with lessons learnt from my travel experiences. In particular, the very fruitful and clear explanation given by Dr. Nabulsi about the importance of first knowing Allah (Subhanahu Wata\'ala), through His creation and signs in the universe in order to worship Him, as it should be. From this perspective, most Muslims know and practice the five pillars of Islam.
            \n\nHowever, like any structure, these five pillars must have a foundation. According to my personal interpretation, this foundation is like the soul of Islam that makes our faith (Imaan) in Allah (Subhanahu Wata'ala) strong. The five pillars of Islam are the body parts that one must know in order to practice our faith with love and thankfulness. Notably, the three most important elements of the foundation of Islam are:

            \n\n1. Al-Eaql (Wisdom)
            \n\n“He grants wisdom to whom He wills; and he to whom wisdom is granted is indeed granted abundant good. But none remember except men of understanding” (Quran 2:269)
            \n\nThis is the most beautiful treasure from Allah (Subhanahu Wata'ala) to humanity in order to guide us to the find the Truth. Quran has put a great amount of importance on using wisdom in all themes including gaining awareness about the existence of Allah (Subhanahu Wata'ala), knowing good from evil, differentiating between truth and lies, knowing the difference between freedom and domination, following the moral and leaving the immoral and finally to find purpose in life.

            \n\n2. Al-Fitrah (Goodness)
            \n\n“So direct your face toward the religion, inclining to truth. Adhere to the Fitrah of Allah upon which He has created all people” (Quran 30:30)
            \n\nGoodness could be interpreted as a DNA-coded Quran that every human is imprinted with from birth. With reference to this concept, new research findings in the field of human biology show that we may be born to be sociable and have the urge to help. Considering my travel experiences, I encountered both good people and bad people everywhere. This illustrated that goodness doesn’t depend on any particular cultural or religious background.

            \n\n3. Al-Tawheed (Law of Divine Oneness)
            \n\n“Allah does not forgive that anything should be associated with Him, but He forgives anything other than this to whomsoever He pleases; and whoever associates anything with Allah, he devises indeed a great sin.” (Quran 4:48)
            \n\nAl-Tawheed refers to the non-existence of coincidence, and that the pathways of our lives do not happen by chance. It is assurance that our entire lives depend on our relationship with Allah (Subhanahu Wata'ala) alone.
            \n\nHe created us with five senses in order to experience the world around us and find His signs. Indeed, the universe is like a silent Quran with so many marks that show the existence and the Beautiful Names of Allah (Subhanahu Wata'ala).
            \n\nFor example, knowing that there are stars billions of light years from earth is undoubtedly a sign to glorify Him by His Beautiful Name “The Great One”. Watching the beautiful smile of a mother holding her baby is a sign of the Love of Allah (Subhanahu Wata'ala) for all human beings by His Beautiful Name “The Loving One”. Listening to waves crashing against the shore reminds us of His Beautiful Name “The Strong One”. The extreme temperatures of a chilly winter or hot summer could be signs to fear the punishment of hell and His Beautiful Name “The Reckoning One”.
            \n\nFinally, the beauty of nature during spring could be a sign of the magnificence of Heaven and His Beautiful Name “The Glorious One”.
            \n\n\nIn conclusion, my current knowledge and perception has led me to conclude that spirituality is needed in Islam in order to be able to perceive that Allah (Subhanahu Wata'ala) governs everything behind the stage of the visible material world. For my part, I realize now that the hidden Hand of Allah (Subhanahu Wata'ala) was guiding me through every event of my life, whether positive or negative. At times this has created beneficial opportunities in my life, and has also steered me away from potentially harmful situations or choices.</item>
        <item>
            In Islam, the human soul is considered a precious creation of Allah, and nurturing it is a fundamental aspect of a believer\'s journey.
            \n\nOne of the most esteemed qualities that adorn the soul is patience, or "Sabr" in Arabic.
            \nSabr is not merely an act of endurance; it is a virtue that elevates the soul and brings it closer to Allah.

            \n\nThis article explores the merits of the soul through the lens of patience in Sunni Islam, highlighting its significance, types, and the rewards it brings to those who embody it.

            \n\nThe Significance of Patience (Sabr)
            \n\nPatience (Sabr) is a virtue deeply revered in Sunni Islam. It is a quality that encompasses various dimensions of life, both in times of ease and adversity. Sabr involves restraining one\'s self from despair and complaints, while remaining steadfast and content in the face of difficulties.

            \n\n1. Spiritual Growth:
            \n\nPatience nurtures spiritual growth by strengthening the connection between the believer and Allah. It is an act of submission to the divine will, recognizing that Allah is the ultimate source of strength and solace.

            \n\n2. Test of Faith:
            \n\nTrials and tribulations are considered tests from Allah. Embracing patience during these tests demonstrates unwavering faith and trust in His wisdom.
            \n\nThe Prophet Muhammad (peace be upon him) said,"Amazing is the affair of the believer, for there is good in every matter of his, and this is not the case with anyone else except in the case of the believer:
            If he is happy, then he thanks Allah, and thus there is good for him, and if he is harmed, then he shows patience, and thus there is good for him"
            \n\n(Sahih Muslim).

            \n\n\nTypes of Patience

            \n\nIn Sunni Islam, there are three main types of patience:

            \n\n1. Patience in Adversity (Sabr \'ala al-musibah):
            \n\nThis is the most commonly known type of patience. It involves remaining steadfast in the face of trials, calamities, and personal hardships. It means enduring suffering with grace and perseverance.

            \n\n2. Patience in Obedience (Sabr \'ala al-ta\'ah):
            \n\nThis type of patience involves maintaining one\'s commitment to acts of worship and obedience to Allah, even when it becomes challenging or burdensome.
            \n\nIt includes being patient in fulfilling religious obligations like prayer, fasting, and charity.

            \n\n3. Patience in Avoiding Sin (Sabr \'an al-ma\'siyah):
            \n\nThis form of patience requires abstaining from sinful actions, thoughts, and desires.
            \n\nIt involves controlling one\'s desires and impulses to remain obedient to Allah\'s commandments.

            \n\nThe Rewards of Patience

            \n\nThe merits of the soul are abundantly rewarded in Islam, and patience is no exception. Allah promises numerous rewards for those who exercise patience in their lives:

            \n\n1. Paradise:
            \n\nThe ultimate reward for patience is Paradise. Allah has promised, "Indeed, the patient will be given their reward without account" (Quran 39:10). This verse highlights the immeasurable and limitless reward that awaits those who persevere with patience.

            \n\n2. Forgiveness:
            \n\nAllah forgives the sins of those who patiently endure hardships.
            \n\nThe Prophet Muhammad (peace be upon him) said,"No fatigue, disease, sorrow, sadness, hurt, or distress afflicts a Muslim, even if it were the prick he receives from a thorn, but that Allah expiates some of his sins for that" (Sahih al-Bukhari).

            \n\n3. Elevation in Status:
            \n\nPatience elevates one\'s status in the sight of Allah.
            \n\nThe Prophet Muhammad (peace be upon him) said,"There is no gift that Allah bestows upon His slave better than patience" (Sahih al-Bukhari).
            \n\nThis implies that those who exhibit patience are held in high esteem by Allah.

            \n\n\nConclusion

            \n\nIn Sunni Islam, the merits of the soul are intricately linked to the practice of patience (Sabr).
            \n\nPatience is a virtue that nourishes the soul, deepens one\'s faith, and brings immense rewards in this life and the Hereafter.
            \n\nBy embracing the various forms of patience and recognizing its significance, Muslims can strive to elevate their souls and draw closer to Allah\'s mercy and guidance.
            </item>
        <item>As the old saying goes, ‘knowledge is power’. Since the first revelation from Allah the Almighty to our beloved Prophet Muhammad ﷺ, the Quran mentions great importance of seeking knowledge in Islam.
            \n\nEvery Muslim is \*obligated*\ to seek knowledge regardless of their gender, age, ethnicity, social status and more. We all have equal rights to education and seeking knowledge to improve and empower ourselves as liberating individuals of the Ummah.
            \n\nBecause of Islam’s focus on the significance of seeking knowledge, exemplary role models of Islam during the Islamic Golden Age like Ibn Sina, Ibn Batutta, al-Khawarizmi, Al-Jazari, and the likes were born to contribute and expand various branches of knowledge to enlighten the whole world, SubhanAllah.
            \n\nThey were some of the pioneers of complex and advanced fields of knowledge like medicine, astronomy, cartography, psychology and more.
            \n\nBefore we get to the whys and hows of seeking knowledge, let us first unravel the Definition of seeking knowledge in Islam, what it means from other Muslim scholars’ perspective.

            \n\nThe Arabic word ‘ilm often translated as “knowledge” implies “knowing about something”.
            \nAcording to one of the prominent figures of Islam, Imam Al-Ghazali, he defines knowledge as ‘the attainment of actual description or representation in the heart.’
            \n\nBased on the view of Prof Syed Naquib al-Attas, knowledge is divided into two based on the manner of its attainment:

            \n\nHusul: The arrival of meaning and description of a thing to the soul.

            \n\nWusul: The arrival of the soul at the right meaning and description of a meaning that is in fact the subject of knowledge.

            \n\nIbn Sina, an extraordinary Muslim scholar defines knowledge as ‘the understanding or discernment of something, which is the reality reflecting itself in the intelligent which has been constantly observing what it is.’ In principle, reality is external from the intelligent.
            \n\nNow that we’ve gotten a good grasp on the concept of knowledge in Islam, let us explicate the Quranic verses and hadiths on seeking knowledge to further understand how essential it is to educate ourselves:
            \n\nQuranic verses and Hadith on Seeking Knowledge:

            \n\nAside from the very famous surah on seeking knowledge, Surah al-’Alaq, where the whole chapter entails the urgency for all Muslims to read or acquire knowledge, there are also other parts of the Quran and hadiths which mention the vitality of seeking knowledge:\n\n

            يَرْفَعِ اللَّهُ الَّذِينَ آمَنُوا مِنكُمْ وَالَّذِينَ أُوتُوا الْعِلْمَ دَرَجَاتٍ ۚ وَاللَّهُ بِمَا تَعْمَلُونَ خَبِيرٌ

            \n\nGod will raise up, by many degrees, those of you who believe and those who have been given knowledge: He is fully aware of what you do. [Qur’an, 58:11]
            \n\nAllah the Glorious Promises that He WILL raise the status of those who are given knowledge. It is evident that the level of the knowledgeable is vastly higher than those who are ignorant.\n\n

            وَسَخَّرَ لَكُم مَّا فِي السَّمَاوَاتِ وَمَا فِي الْأَرْضِ جَمِيعًا مِّنْهُ ۚ إِنَّ فِي ذَٰلِكَ لَآيَاتٍ لِّقَوْمٍ يَتَفَكَّرُونَ

            \n\nHe has subjected all that is in the heavens and the earth for your benefit, as a gift from Him. There truly are signs in this for those who reflect. [Qur’an, 45:13]\n\n

            إِنَّمَا يَخْشَى اللَّهَ مِنْ عِبَادِهِ الْعُلَمَاءُ ۗ إِنَّ اللَّهَ عَزِيزٌ غَفُورٌ

            \n\nAt is those of His servants who have knowledge who stand in true awe of God. God is almighty, most forgiving. [Qur’an, 35:28]

            \n\nIf you notice, in many parts of the Quran Allah mentions that those who contemplate and reflect, especially when utilising their intellectual faculty, will find the Signs that the ignorant don’t.
            \n\nKeep on learning and discover the wonders of the world, and within those beauties will you find the great Signs of Allah the Almighty. By seeking knowledge, you will expand your worldview, make you more mature and wiser, InshaAllah.

            \n\n “Seeking knowledge is a duty upon every Muslim (and Muslimah)” [Prophet Muhammad ﷺ]

            \n\nOne of the biggest struggles Muslims come across today is the blatant technological distraction which lures us to waste our time on entertainment rather than seeking knowledge!
            \n\nThe hadith on seeking knowledge above is one of the most common hadiths we often come across at least once in our lifetime. This hadith encapsulates the meaning of our responsibilities as Muslims, which is to seek knowledge whenever we can.

            \n\n“Whoever takes a path in search of knowledge, Allah will cause him to walk in one of the paths to Paradise. Indeed the angels will lower their wings in great pleasure with the one who seeks knowledge.” [Prophet Muhammad ﷺ]

            \n\n“If Allah intends goodness for a person, He gives him the understanding of the religion.” [Prophet Muhammad ﷺ]

            \n\nLast but not least, here are some of the hadiths on the benefits of seeking knowledge. It is mentioned in the hadith above that Allah the Glorious will open a path to Paradise for those who pursue knowledge, and if Allah intends goodness on a Muslim, He will endow that person with the understanding of Islam.

            \n\nIn retrospect, we can deduce that Allah the Merciful indeed encourages all to tread the path of knowledge and will reward us for doing so. So, get ready to embark on a spiritual journey of seeking knowledge, and see the difference in the new you!
            \nThe Three Divisions of Knowledge in Islam:
            \n\nGenerally, there are many branches of knowledge, but what does Islam say about the division and integration of knowledge in Islam? According to Ahmad Tijani and Muhamad Zahiri (2013), there are three categories of knowledge according to the Qur’an (62:2 and 96:1-5) that forms a strong foundation of the integration of knowledge:
            \n\n1. Religious Knowledge:  The essence of the Islamic religious knowledge and experience is tawhid. It is the main foundation of the Islamic intellectual discourse (Bakar, 2008). This makes the Islamic intellectual tradition a tawhidic epistemology.
            \n\n2. Pure Sciences:  a science depending on deductions from demonstrated truths, such as mathematics or logic, or studied without regard to practical applications. This science is needed to enable Muslims have a better understanding of religious or sacred knowledge.
            \n\n3. Natural Sciences:  a branch of science that deals with the physical world. Allah the Glorious has mentioned in many parts of the Quran that capture the explorations of natural phenomena (Mehdi Golshani, n.d.). The exploration of nature should be made positive and ultimately, it should be a reflection about the glory and excellence of Allah the Almighty.

            \n\n\nThe Two Types of Knowledge in Islam:
            \n\nAccording to most Muslim scholars, Islamic knowledge is classified into two types:

            \n\n1. Individually Obligatory Knowledge (farḍ ʿayn):
            \n\nThis type of knowledge refers to the fundamentals of Islamic beliefs that every Muslim is obligated to know. Seeking this knowledge is a must for each and every Muslim.
            \n\nThe ruling for not acquiring such knowledge is sinful and Muslims are held accountable for the ignorance in this type of knowledge. For instance, one must know the pillars of Islam and Iman, the fundamentals of worship, fiqh rulings of certain deeds and so on.

            \n\n2. Communally Obligatory Knowledge (farḍ kifâyah):
            \n\nThis type of knowledge is not an obligation for every individual, but rather falls upon a “sufficient number” within the community as a whole. Hence, if a group of individuals in the community acquire this kind of knowledge, other individuals are exempted from this duty.
            \n\nThe ruling for this type of knowledge is sunnah mu’akkadah. For example, pursuing Law or medicine, and other professions imperative for the welfare of society.

            \n\n\nThe 5 Tips to Seek Knowledge in Islam:
            \n\nOf course, to seek knowledge is to be familiar with the etiquette, preparations and the correct methods. Before you begin your journey of seeking knowledge, you should bear a few things in mind:

            \n\n1. Rectify your intentions
            \n\nJust like any other deed, you have to determine the reasons for doing something. Why do you want to seek knowledge? Are you mentally and spiritually ready to embark on your adventure? What drives you to start?
            \n\nThese are all questions you should have answers to. If it helps, you could even jot down your intentions in your personal journal to keep your intentions in check every day. The last thing you need is to corrupt your intentions by showing off the knowledge you possess!
            \n\n"Actions are but by intention and every man shall have but that which he intended. Thus he whose migration was for Allah and His messenger, his migration was for Allah and His messenger, and he whose migration was to achieve some worldly benefit or to take some woman in marriage, his migration was for that for which he migrated."
            \n[Prophet Muhammad ﷺ]

            \n\n2. Choose Your Teachers Wisely
            \n\nSimplyIslam Academy offers Islamic courses online, from Hadith, Fiqh, Sirah, Tasawwuf and more. Our Muslim scholars are selected based on their credebility and exceptional qualifications, and our platform is deeply rooted in the way of Ahlus Sunnah wal Jama’ah.
            \n\nSo, if you would like to start your journey towards Islamic knowledge, our platform can be a great stepping stone for you to expand your Islamic worldview, InshaAllah.

            \n\n3. Attend Classes at Your Local Mosque
            \n\nIf you are allowed to go to the mosque, it is an incredible opportunity for you to seek knowledge face-to-face with the instructor. This will give you a better learning experience as you could ask whatever questions that come to your mind and interact with your instructor and other participants.
            \n\nDepending on your local mosques, they might have fixed schedules every day when lectures will be conducted.
            \n\nSo, perhaps if lectures are conducted after Maghrib, you could stay there and perform Isha’ congregational prayer as well! As they say, kill two birds with one stone.

            \n\nHere are some etiquette to keep in mind when you’re attending classes or lectures:
            \n
            \n - Ask questions!Leave early so you can arrive early/on time to the mosque
            \n - Put your cell phone on silent (or turn if off) to prevent disruptions
            \n - Sit as close as you can to the instructor
            \n - Jot down any notes for memory retention
            \n\n4. Make Du’a Before you Study
            \nJust like before you eat, before you sleep, there is also a du’a for you to recite before you seek knowledge.
            \n\nThese du’as may be simple, but when you truly believe in them and recite with a sincere heart, it does wonders for your intellectual faculties! You will find that you retain information much easier, understand concepts much more easily and utilise time effectively, InshaAllah.\n

            اللَّهُمَّ إِنِّي أَعُوذُ بِكَ مِنْ عِلْمٍ لَا يَنْفَعُ وَمِنْ قَلْبٍ لَا يَخْشَعُ وَمِنْ نَفْسٍ لَا تَشْبَعُ وَمِنْ دَعْوَةٍ لَا يُسْتَجَابُ لَهَا

            \n\n“O Allah, I seek refuge in You from knowledge which does not benefit, from a heart that does not entertain the fear (of Allah), from a soul that is not satisfied and the supplication that is not answered.”\n

            َللَّهُمَّ اَكْرِمْنْيْ بِنُوْرِ الْفَهْمِ وَ خَرَّجَنِيْ مِنْ ظُلُمَاتِ الْوَهْمِ وَ افْتَحْ عَلَيْنَا اَبْوَابَ عِلْمَكَ، وَ انْشُرْ عَلَيْنَا خُزَّانَ مَعْرِفَتِكَ يَا اَرْحَمَ الرَّاحِمِيْنَ، اَللَّهُمَّ وَفِّقْنِيْ فِىْ الْمُطَالَعَةِ بِحَلِّ جَمِيْعِ مُشْكِلاَتِ الْمَسَآئِلِ مِنَ الْكُتُبِ بِرَحْمَتِكَ يَا اَرْحَمَ الرَّاحِمِيْنَ

            \n\n“Oh Allah, honor me by the light of understanding and take me out from the darkness of doubt and open upon us the doors of your knowledge and open upon us the treasure of your recognition, oh the best of the Merciful ones. Oh Allah, and give me Tawfeeq to study and solve all the difficult problems through books. By your mercy, oh the best of the merciful ones.”\n

            رَبِّ اشْرَحْ لِي صَدْرِي وَيَسِّرْ لِي أَمْرِي وَاحْلُلْ عُقْدَةً مِّن لِّسَانِي يَفْقَهُوا قَوْلِي

            \n\n“O my Sustainer! Open up my heart and make my task easy for me, and loosen the knot from my tongue so that they might fully understand my speech.”

            \n\n5. Seek Knowledge by Reading Islamic Books
            \n\nJust like the first revelation Allah has descended upon our Blessed Prophet Muhammad ﷺ, we are encouraged to read some insightful Islamic books to enhance our understanding of Islam, and increase our love to our deen, InshaAllah. Here are a few recommendations for you to start with:\n

            \n - The Great Theft by Dr Khaled Abou El Fadl
            \n - The Broken Chain by Sidi Aftab Malik
            \n - Reclaim Your Heart by Yasmin Mogahed
            \n - Secrets of Divine Love by A. Helwa
            \n\nWe hope that these few tips will help you in your journey to seek Islamic knowledge, and may Allah ease any difficulty that comes your way. Seeking knowledge is indeed a noble deed that all Muslims should try and invest time in, so let’s empower our Ummah through passion and love for Islamic knowledge, InshaAllah.</item>
         </string-array>

    <string-array name="arr_dzikir_doa_harian">
        <item>Sebelum tidur</item>
        <item>Ketika mimpi buruk</item>
        <item>Bangun tidur</item>
        <item>Masuk WC/kamar mandi</item>
        <item>Keluar WC/kamar mandi</item>
        <item>Sebelum wudhu</item>
        <item>Setelah wudhu</item>
        <item>Mengenakan pakaian</item>
        <item>Melepas pakaian</item>
        <item>Keluar rumah</item>
        <item>Masuk rumah</item>
        <item>Pergi ke Masjid</item>
        <item>Masuk ke Masjid</item>
        <item>Keluar dari Masjid</item>
        <item>Ketika mendengar Adzan</item>
        <item>Setelah adzan</item>
        <item>Bersin</item>
        <item>Kepada orang yang berbuat baik kepadamu</item>
        <item>Ketika marah</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="arr_lafaz_dzikir_doa_harian">
        <item>Mengumpulkan dua telapak tangan, lalu ditiup dan dibacakan:\n\nSurat Al-Ikhlas:\nبِسْمِ اللَّهِ الرَّحْمَٰنِ الرَّحِيمِ \nقُلْ هُوَ اللَّهُ أَحَدٌ ﴿١﴾ اللَّهُ الصَّمَدُ ﴿٢﴾ لَمْ يَلِدْ وَلَمْ يُولَدْ ﴿٣﴾ وَلَمْ يَكُنْ لَهُ كُفُوًا أَحَدٌ ﴿٤﴾ \n\nSurat Al-Falaq:\nبِسْمِ اللَّهِ الرَّحْمَٰنِ الرَّحِيمِ \nقُلْ اَعُوْذُ بِرَبِّ الْفَلَقِۙ ﴿١﴾ مِنْ شَرِّ مَا خَلَقَۙ ﴿٢﴾ وَمِنْ شَرِّ غَاسِقٍ اِذَا وَقَبَۙ ﴿٣﴾ وَمِنْ شَرِّ النَّفّٰثٰتِ فِى الْعُقَدِۙ ﴿٤﴾ وَمِنْ شَرِّ حَاسِدٍ اِذَا حَسَدَ ﴿٥﴾ \n\nAn-Naas:\nبِسْمِ اللَّهِ الرَّحْمَٰنِ الرَّحِيمِ \nقُلْ اَعُوْذُ بِرَبِّ النَّاسِۙ ﴿١﴾ مَلِكِ النَّاسِۙ ﴿٢﴾ اِلٰهِ النَّاسِۙ ﴿٣﴾ مِنْ شَرِّ الْوَسْوَاسِ ەۙ الْخَنَّاسِۖ ﴿٤﴾ الَّذِيْ يُوَسْوِسُ فِيْ صُدُوْرِ النَّاسِۙ ﴿٥﴾ مِنَ الْجِنَّةِ وَالنَّاسِ ﴿٦﴾\nAyat Kursi:\nٱللَّهُ لَآ إِلَٰهَ إِلَّا هُوَ ٱلْحَىُّ ٱلْقَيُّومُ ۚ لَا تَأْخُذُهُۥ سِنَةٌ وَلَا نَوْمٌ ۚ لَّهُۥ مَا فِى ٱلسَّمَٰوَٰتِ وَمَا فِى ٱلْأَرْضِ ۗ مَن ذَا ٱلَّذِى يَشْفَعُ عِندَهُۥٓ إِلَّا بِإِذْنِهِۦ ۚ يَعْلَمُ مَا بَيْنَ أَيْدِيهِمْ وَمَا خَلْفَهُمْ ۖ وَلَا يُحِيطُونَ بِشَىْءٍ مِّنْ عِلْمِهِۦٓ إِلَّا بِمَا شَآءَ ۚ وَسِعَ كُرْسِيُّهُ ٱلسَّمَٰوَٰتِ وَٱلْأَرْضَ ۖ وَلَا يَـُٔودُهُۥ حِفْظُهُمَا ۚ وَهُوَ ٱلْعَلِىُّ ٱلْعَظِيمُ\nKetika sudah berbaring baca doa:\nاَللَّهُمَّ أَسْلَمْتُ نَفْسِيْ إِلَيْكَ، وَفَوَّضْتُ أَمْرِيْ إِلَيْكَ، وَوَجَّهْتُ وَجْهِيَ إِلَيْكَ، وَأَلْجَأْتُ ظَهْرِيْ إِلَيْكَ، رَغْبَةً وَرَهْبَةً إِلَيْكَ، لاَ مَلْجَأَ وَلاَ مَنْجَا مِنْكَ إِلاَّ إِلَيْكَ، آمَنْتُ بِكِتَابِكَ الَّذِيْ أَنْزَلْتَ وَبِنَبِيِّكَ الَّذِيْ أَرْسَلْتَ\n\nبِاسْمِكَ رَبِّيْ وَضَعْتُ جَنْبِيْ، وَبِكَ أَرْفَعُهُ، فَإِنْ أَمْسَكْتَ نَفْسِيْ فَارْحَمْهَا، وَإِنْ أَرْسَلْتَهَا فَاحْفَظْهَا بِمَا تَحْفَظُ بِهِ عِبَادَكَ الصَّالِحِيْنَ</item>
        <item>Membaca isti\'adzah:\nأَعُوذُ بِاَللَّهِ مِنَ الشَّيْطَانِ الرَّجِيمِْ\nlalu meludah tipis (meniup disertai sedikit liur) ke sebelah kirinya sebanyak tiga kali.\nDemikian juga merubah posisi tidur. Bahkan dianjurkan untuk bangun dan shalat.</item>
        <item>الحَمْدُ ِللهِ الَّذِي أَحْيَاناَ بَعْدَ مَا أَمَاتَنَا وَ إِلَيْهِ النُّشُوْرُ</item>
        <item>اللَّهُمَّ إِنِّى أَعُوذُ بِكَ مِنَ الْخُبُثِ وَالْخَبَائِثِ</item>
        <item>غُفْرَانَكَ</item>
        <item>بسم الله</item>
        <item>Pertama:\nأَشْهَدُ أَنْ لاَ إِلهَ إِلاَّ اللهُ وَحْدَهُ لاَ شَرِيْكَ لَهُ وَأَشْهَدُ أَنَّ مُحَمَّدًا عَبْدُهُ وَرَسُوْلُهُ\n\nKedua:\nسُبْحَانَكَ اللَّهُمَّ وَبِحَمْدِكَ، أَشْهَدُ أَنْ لاَ إِلَـهَ إِلاَّ أَنْتَ، أَسْتَغْفِرُكَ وَأَتُوْبُ إِلَيْكَ</item>
        <item>اَلْحَمْدُ لِلَّهِ الَّذِيْ كَسَانِيْ هَذَا الثَّوْبَ وَرَزَقَنِيْهِ مِنْ غَيْرِ حَوْلٍ مِنِّيْ وَلَا قُوَّةٍ</item>
        <item>بسم الله</item>
        <item>بِسْمِ اللهِ تَوَكَّلْتُ عَلَى اللهِ لَا حَوْلَ وَلَا قُوَّةَ إِلَّا بِاللهِ</item>
        <item>Pertama:\nبسم الله\n\Kedua:\nالسلام عليكم</item>
        <item>اللّهُمَّ اجْعَلْ فِي قَلْبِيْ نُوْراً، وَفِي لِسَانِي نُوْراً، وَاجْعَلْ وَفِي سَمْعِي نُوْراً، وَاجْعَلْ فِي بَصَرِي نُوْراً، وَاجْعَلْ مِنْ خَلْفِي نُوْراً، وَمِنْ أَمَامِي نُوْراً، وَاجْعَلْ مِنْ فَوْقِي نُوْراً، وَمِنْ تَحْتِي نُوْراً، اللّهُمَّ أَعْطِنِي نُوْراً</item>
        <item>Pertama:\nاللَّهُمَّ افْتَحْ لِي أَبْوَابَ رَحْمَتِكَ\n\nKedua:\nوَالصَّلَاةُ وَالسَّلاَمُ عَلَى رَسُولِ اللهِ اللَّهُمَّ افْتَحْ لِي أَبْوَابَ رَحْمَتِكَ\n\nKetiga:\nأَعُوذُ بِاللَّهِ الْعَظِيمِ، وَبِوَجْهِهِ الْكَرِيمِ، وَسُلْطَانِهِ الْقَدِيمِ، مِنَ الشَّيْطَانِ الرَّجِيمِ</item>
        <item>اللَّهُمَّ إِنِّيْ أَسْأَلُكَ مِنْ فَضْلِكَ</item>
        <item>Seseorang yang mendengarkan adzan, hendaklah mengucapkan sebagaimana yang diucapkan oleh muadzin, kecuali dalam kalimat:\nHayya \'alash shalaah\n\ndan\n\nHayya \'alal falaah. Maka mengucapkan:\nلاحول ولا قوة الا بالله</item>
        <item>اللَّهُمَّ رَبَّ هَذِهِ الدَّعْوَةِ التَّامَّةِ ، وَالصَّلاَةِ القَائِمَةِ آتِ مُحَمَّدًا الوَسِيلَةَ وَالفَضِيلَةَ، وَابْعَثْهُ مَقَامًا مَحْمُودًا الَّذِي وَعَدْتَهُ</item>
        <item>Yang bersin mengucapkan:\nالحمد لله\nYang mendengar hamdalah mengucapkan:\nيَرْحَمُكَ اللهُ\nBila teman atau saudaranya mengucapkan (yarhamukallah), maka yang bersin membalas dengan:\nيَهْدِيْكُمُ اللهُ وَيُصْلِحُ بَالَكُمْ</item>
        <item>جزاك الله خيراً</item>
        <item>أَعُوذُ بِاللَّهِ مِنَ الشَّيْطَانِ الرَّجِيمِ</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="arr_terjemah_dzikir_doa_harian">
        <item>Surat Al-Ikhlas:\n\"Katakanlah: Dialah Allah Yang Maha Esa. Allah adalah ilah yang bergantung kepada-Nya segala urusan. Dia tidak beranak dan tiada pula diperanakkan. Dan tidak ada seorang pun yang setara dengan Dia.\"\n\nSurat Al-Falaq:\n\"Katakanlah: Aku berlindung kepada Rabb yang menguasai Subuh. Dari kejahatan makhluk-Nya. Dan dari kejahatan malam apabila telah gelap gulita. Dan dari kejahatan wanita-wanita tukang sihir yang menghembus pada buhul-buhul. Dan dari kejahatan orang yang dengki apabila ia dengki.\"\n\nAn-Naas:\n\"Katakanlah: Aku berlindung kepada Rabb manusia. Raja manusia. Sembahan manusia. Dari kejahatan (bisikan) syaitan yang biasa bersembunyi. Yang membisikkan (kejahatan) ke dalam dada manusia. Dari jin dan manusia.\"\n\nAyat Kursi:\n\"Allah, tidak ada sesembahan yang berhak disembah kecuali Dia Yang Hidup Kekal lagi terus-menerus mengurus (makhluk-Nya). Tidak mengantuk dan tidak tidur. Kepunyaan-Nya apa yang di langit dan di bumi. Siapakah yang dapat memberi syafa\'at di sisi Allah tanpa izin-Nya? Allah mengetahui apa-apa yang dia hadapan dan di belakang mereka, dan mereka tidak mengetahui apa-apa ilmu Allah melainkan apa yang dikehendaki-Nya. Kursi Allah melliputi langit dan bumi, dan Allah tidak merasa berat memelihara keduanya. Dan Allah Maha Tinggi lagi Maha Besar.\"\n\nKetika sudah berbaring baca doa:\n\"Ya Allah, aku serahkan jiwaku kepada-mu, aku hadapkan wajahku kepada-Mu, aku serahkan urusanku kepada-Mu, aku sandarkan punggungku kepada-Mu, karena mengharapkan (pahala-Mu) dan takut (adzab-Mu). Tiada tempat bersandar dan menyelamatkan diri dari (hukuman)-Mu kecuali kepada-Mu. Aku beriman kepada Kitab-Mu yang Engkau turunkan, dan kepada Nabi-Mu yang Engkau utus.\"\n\n\"Dengan nama Engkau, wahai Rabbku, aku meletakkan lambungku. Dan dengan nama-Mu pula aku bangun dari padanya. Apabila Engkau menahan rohku maka berilah rahmat padanya. Tapi apabila Engkau melepaskannya maka peliharalah, sebagaimana Engkau memelihara hamba-hambaMu yang shalih.\"</item>
        <item>\"Aku memohon perlindungan kepada Allah dari setan yang terkutuk.\"</item>
        <item>\"Segala puji bagi Allah, yang membangunkan kami setelah ditidurkanNya dan kepadaNya kami dikumpulkan.\"</item>
        <item>\"Dengan nama Allah. Ya Allah, sesungguhnya aku berlindung kepada-Mu dari keburukan dan jin.\"</item>
        <item>\"Aku minta ampun kepadaMu.\"</item>
        <item>\"Dengan nama Allah (aku berwudhu).\"</item>
        <item>Pertama:\n\"Aku bersaksi, bahwa tidak ada sesembahan yang berhak disembah kecuali Allah, Yang Maha Esa dan tiada sekutu bagiNya. Aku bersaksi, bahwa Muhammad adalah hamba dan utusanNya.\"\n\nKedua:\n\"Maha Suci Engkau ya Allah, aku memujiMu. Aku bersaksi bahwa tidak ada sesembahan yang berhak disembah kecuali Engkau, aku minta ampun dan betaubat kepada-Mu.\"</item>
        <item>\"Segala puji bagi Allah yang memberi pakaian ini kepadaku sebagai rezeki dariNya tanpa daya dan kekuatan dariku.\"</item>
        <item>\"Dengan nama Allah (aku meletakkan baju).\"</item>
        <item>\"Dengan nama Allah, aku bertawakkal kepada Allah, tiada daya dan kekuatan kecuali dengan pertolongan Allah.\"</item>
        <item>Pertama:\n\"Dengan nama Allah.\"\n\n\Kedua:\n\"Semoga keselamatan atas kalian.\"</item>
        <item>\"Ya Allah, jadikanlah cahaya di hatiku, cahaya di lidahku, cahaya di pendengaranku, cahaya di penglihatanku, cahaya dari belakangku, cahaya dari hadapanku, cahaya dari atasku, cahaya dari bawahku. Ya Allah, berilah aku cahaya.\"</item>
        <item>Pertama:\n\"Ya Allah, bukalah pintu-pintu rahmatMu untukku.\"\n\nKedua:\n\"Semoga shalawat dan salam terlimpahkan kepada Rasulullah. Ya Allah, bukalah pintu-pintu rahmatMu untukku.\"\n\nKetiga:\n\"Aku berlindung kepada Allah Yang Maha Agung, dengan wajah-Nya Yang Mulia dan kekuasaan-Nya yang abadi, dari setan yang terkuturk.\" </item>
        <item>\"Ya Allah, sesungguhnya aku minta kepadaMu dari karuniaMu.\"</item>
        <item>\"Tidak ada daya dan upaya kecuali dengan pertolongan Allah\"</item>
        <item>\"Ya Allah, Rabb Pemilik panggilan yang sempurna (adzan) ini dan shalat (wajib) yang didirikan. Berilah Al-Wasilah (derajat di Surga, yang tidak akan diberikan selain kepada Nabi) dan fadhilah kepada Muhammad. Dan bangkitkan beliau sehingga bisa menempati maqam terpuji yang telah Engkau janjikan.\"</item>
        <item>(Alhamdulillah) artinya:\n\"Segala puji bagi Allah.\"\n\n(Yarhamukallah) artinya:\n\"Semoga Allah memberikan rahmat kepadamu.\"\n\n\"(Yahdiikumullaahu wa yushlihu baalakum) artinya:\n\"Semoga Allah memberi petunjuk kepadamu dan memperbaiki keadaanmu.\"</item>
        <item>\"Semoga Allah membalasmu dengan kebaikan.\"</item>
        <item>\"Aku berlindung kepada Allah dari godaan syaitan yang terkutuk.\"</item>
    </string-array>
</resources>